The greatest buffaloer of them all!
Buffalo Bill and the Indians, or Sitting Bull's History Lesson is
a western, comedy film directed by Robert Altman.
Buffalo Bill plans to put on his own Wild West sideshow, and
Chief Sitting Bull has agreed to appear in it.
However, Sitting Bull has his own hidden agenda,
involving the President and General Custer.
The Star (William F. Cody), played by Paul Newman.
The Producer (Nate Salisbury), played by Joel Grey.
The Publicist (Maj. John Burke), played by Kevin McCarthy.
The Relative (Ed Goodman), played by Harvey Keitel.
The Journalist (Prentiss Ingraham), played by Allan F. Nicholls.
The Sure Shot (Annie Oakley), played by Geraldine Chaplin.
Buffalo Bill and the Indians, or Sitting Bull's History Lesson is a 1976 revisionist Western
film directed by Robert Altman and based on the 1968 play Indians by Arthur Kopit.
It stars Paul Newman as William F.
Cody, alias Buffalo Bill, along with Geraldine Chaplin, Will Sampson, Joel Grey,
Harvey Keitel, and Burt Lancaster as Bill's biographer, Ned Buntline.
It was filmed in Panavision by cinematographer Paul Lohmann.
As in his earlier film M*A*S*H, Altman skewers an American historical myth of heroism, in this
case the notion that noble white men fighting bloodthirsty savages won the West.
However, the film was poorly received at the time of its release,
as the country was celebrating its bicentennial.
The film explores themes of based on play or musical, wild west,
wild west show, 19th century, revisionist western.
The tone is lighthearted.